#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/1234sanjeev (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

IΡ

Wireless

**Mobile Devices** 

## Languages

English

#### **Patents**

Dynamic Route Exchange Methods and systems for a distributed provider edge

# Sanjeev Tyagi

WE ARE HIRING! Data Scientists & Data Engineers at all levels in Bangalore & Chennai. Look for "Global Al Accelerator" in jobs.ericsson.com

Bengaluru

# Summary

Technology executive with extensive global leadership experience leading teams across US, Europe, & India. For the better part of last 2 decades, I've built networking products of multi-dimensional complexity for telcos as well as enterprises. I also bring deep, hands-on experience with incubating and scaling MNC R&D operations.

### Specialties:

- Razor sharp execution focus "Get It Done"
- Product leadership of large, cross-discipline, multi-site, multicultural teams
- End-to-end product life cycle management (concept to deployment to end-of-life)
- Open source engagement
- Agile development methodologies
- Leading small scale incubations to larger (>500 member) teams
- Negotiated business partnership terms/SLAs with 3rd party HW/SW vendors
- Handled sensitive customer relations in deployments with significant revenue repercussions
- Exec level site management: industry connect, finance, branding, HR, operations, HQ management
- Key technologies: Cloud, Virtualization, SDN, NFV, Security, IP, WLAN, Network transformation

# Experience

Ericsson

14 years 1 month

Vice President & Head of the India Hub for the Global Al Accelerator
Page 1 of 3

#### February 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

- Head of the India hub for Ericsson's Global Artificial Intelligence Accelerator (GAIA)
- Managing Director (site head) for Ericsson R&D Bangalore

Vice President & Global Head of Ericsson's SDN & Cloud Networking Group

June 2013 - February 2019 (5 years 9 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

- Managing Director for Ericsson R&D, Bangalore
- Global head of Ericsson's SDN & Cloud Networking product engineering

Senior Director, Engineering

June 2010 - June 2013 (3 years 1 month)

Bengaluru Area, India

- Launched Ericsson's IP & Broadband R&D center in Bangalore
- Scaled the team to eventually take over > 80% of IP product development portfolio

Director, Engineering

August 2006 - June 2010 (3 years 11 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- Led execution/delivery of several strategic initiatives post-acquisition of Redback by Ericsson

#### Cisco

**Engineering Manager** 

October 2004 - August 2006 (1 year 11 months)

Airespace (acquired by Cisco)

Managed end-to-end delivery of the 1st release integrating Cisco's Access Points with Airespace's centralized WLAN controller. Sponsored partner initiatives such as CCX (Cisco Client eXtensions) & BCW (Business Class Wireless). Interfaced with partner silicon vendors and orchestrated inter-op initiatives.

**Cosine Communications** 

**Engineering Manager** 

June 2000 - September 2004 (4 years 4 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Delivered CoSine's 1st BGP/MPLS VPNs, Stateful Firewall, & IPsec VPNs (deployed @ global Tier-1 carriers)

Cadence Design Systems
Software Engineer/Engineering Manager
August 1996 - June 2000 (3 years 11 months)

Led a team of engineers to deliver releases of Cadence Software Infrastructure for Electronic Design Automation applications

Integrated Silicon Systems
Software Engineer
August 1994 - August 1996 (2 years 1 month)

Development of Electronic Design Automation technology & tools

# Education

Indian Institute of Management, Bangalore

AMP, Executive Management & Leadership Program · (2011 - 2012)

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Master's Degree, Computer Science · (1992 - 1994)

Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani BS, CS · (1987 - 1991)